Ayodele Abigail

🕈 Abuja, Nigeria 🛮 ayodeleabigailofficial@gmail.com 🔲 07066301932 🛅 in/ayodeleabigail/

https://pearlsilver35.github.io/Ayodele-Abigail/

SUMMARY

A software developer with 6+ years of experience in developing web applications with strongest skills being PHP and MYSQL. Experienced in designing system architectures and solutions for rapid scaling. Have significant experience working in startups and fast-moving teams with fixed deadlines. Flexible with different technologies and methodologies, and so am able to learn and adapt to new environments quickly.

EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Developer UPilot Inc.

March 2022 - Present, Mauritius

UPilot is a sales CRM that offers advanced functionalities in a simplified way, providing an alternative to complex legacy CRM systems.

As part of the team, I work on bug fixing and implementing new functionalities using technologies such as PHP, MySQL, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Linux, and GIT, and following Agile methodology.

The project is live and used by fast-growing companies, improving their productivity and providing management with unprecedented insight into their pipelines

Backend Developer

Supremelogic Integrated LTD

January 2021 - November 2021, Lagos

As a contract backend developer on the Where We All Meet project,

I worked remotely the team using Laravel, reimplemented the project's previous fuel PHP backend, provided API endpoints for the mobile and web UI teams, and integrated Twilio SMS API.

Additionally, I refactored and optimized the matching algorithm, resulting in better performance and easier maintenance.

Software Developer

Page Financials LTD

September 2019 - March 2022, Lagos

As a full stack developer at Page Financials, a microfinance bank, I delivered various software solutions, including an HRMS solution, task management system, websites, business loans solution, inventory management system, and Paycode integration for cardless withdrawals.

My role involved working closely with the development team and stakeholders to gather requirements, design, develop and deploy software solutions that met the needs of the business.

I leveraged my skills in PHP (LAMP Stack) and other relevant technologies to deliver robust and efficient software solutions that improved the operations of the bank.

Software Developer

Access Solutions LTD

July 2017 - May 2019, Abuja

My job functions included web development, developing QA processes and procedures, directing the QA team, identifying bugs and issues, software documentation, automated and manual security testing, software support, trainings, and cross-browser/platform testing.

With my expertise in these areas, I was able to ensure that our software solutions were of the highest quality and met the needs of our clients.

EDUCATION

B.Sc. Computer Science

Oduduwa University, Ipetumodu. · Osun State, Nigeria · 2016

CERTIFICATIONS

Information Technology Infrastructure Library (ITIL)

SOBCA · 2018

Microsoft Office Specialist

Microsoft · 2014

SKILLS

Software: Css, Javascript Jquery, Html, Apache, Php, Lamp, Linux, SSH, Putty, Jira, Git, Bit Bucket, Scss, Bootstrap, Mvc, Restful, Backend, Fullstack, Python, DevOps, Nginx Apache, Yaml, Ansible Playbook, Postman, Selenium, MySQL

Soft Skills: Leadership, Coaching Mentoring, Training

PROJECTS

Interswitch Paycode Webservice

Page Financials LTD · July 2021 - August 2021

As part of the team responsible for integrating Interswitch Paycode into a web service, I handled the backend development using PHP.

This involved creating six endpoints for Paycode generation, ReQuery, Cancelling, Authorization, Reversal, and Transaction check.

The Paycode Technology enabled cardless withdrawals from ATMs.

Human Resource Management System (HRMS)

Page Financials LTD · January 2020 - December 2021

The Human Resource Management System (HRMS) is a web application designed to automate HR tasks, including payroll management, staff onboarding, leave management, employee management, and training management.

As a backend developer for this project, I utilized the LAMP stack and provided an API for the frontend developers.

The system included a role-based permission system and customizable dynamic workflows for approvals, making it both secure and flexible.

UI/UX Design

Zitra Investment • March 2022 - March 2022

Developed Zitra Investment and Loans Company website using HTML, CSS, and JS based on PSD designs.

UI/UX Design

Second Caesar Investment • February 2022 - February 2022

For Second Caesar, a prominent provider of payment and banking solutions, I implemented their corporate website using HTML, CSS, and JS.

The design was based on PSD files provided by the client, and I ensured that the website was fully responsive and visually appealing.